Offsets are useful tools for scenario analysis.
在进行情境分析时 Offset 函数能提供很大的帮助
We can see how in this example when we change the scenario,
现在 我们就一起来看看 本例中 当情境变化时
it changes the assumptions here,
假设也会随之变化
and when the assumptions are changed,
当假设变化了
it changes the forecasted Sinek metrics here.
所预测的指标也会跟着变化
Let's build one scenario analysis.
现在 我们来构建一个情境分析
I split up the video into various steps.
对于具体的操作步骤 我会分多个视频进行讲解
So, they're building on each concept.
争取把其中涉及的每一个概念都讲透彻
For starters, lets define the four steps to take to create a financial forecast.
首先 我要解释一下创建财务预测时需采取的四个步骤
Step 1 is to calculate
第 1 步
the operating statistics that include the gross and operating margin, and revenue growth.
统计各项运营数据 包括毛利润率和营业利润率 以及收入增长
This is all based on the historical data,
这些都要用到历史数据
which you can find in the income statement over here.
这个损益表里能找到相应数据
So, this is step 1.
第 1 步就完成了
The first box here.
填入标注为 1 的蓝色方框
Step 2 is to create the scenarios.
第 2 步 创建情境
I have them here in this box here.
对应到标注为 2 的蓝色方框
So, this is the scenario that we are going to be creating.
准备在这里创建情境
Typically, we have a strong base and weak case.
通常会有优势情境 (strong base) 和弱势情境 (weak case)
Some business analysts choose to have two additional scenarios as well,
有些业务分析师还会选择另外其他两种情境
we're going to stick with three cases.
通常是三种情境
Then come the assumptions as part of step 3.
接着 第 3 步是假设
These assumptions change in response to the scenario that is chosen over here.
这些假设会随着在此选择的情境而改变
This is where we're going to use offset.
这里就会用到 offset 函数
Finally, step 4 may be develop the forecasted scenarios that
最后 第 4 步是要创建预测情境
change dynamically based on
要将预测情境设定为随着所选情境的改变而改变
the scenarios that are chosen because that affects the assumptions,
因为所选的情境会影响假设情况
and the assumptions go inside the forecasted metrics.
而假设情况会体现到各项预测指标中
So, for step 1,
对于第 1 步
we need to calculate
需根据历史数据
our gross and operating margin here for a based on a historical data.
来计算毛利润率和营业利润率
So, we have this original data that we have seen before,
这些是我们之前见过的原数据
and the gross margin is basically one minus the cost of revenue or cost of goods sold,
毛利润率就是 1 减去…
those two terms are interchangeable over the total revenue.
…营收成本 (或称销货成本) 与总收入之比
So, you plug in this formula in here,
在此输入公式
copy and paste it, and it gives us the gross margin.
复制粘贴公式 得出毛利润率
For operating margin, this is your operating profit over your total revenue.
营业利润率则是营业利润与总收入之比
So, now we have our historical margin ratios here.
这些是我们以往的利润率
I've plugged them in here using our index and match functions.
我用了 Index 函数和 Match 函数来嵌入这些数据
So, I've referred to this as the named box for gross margin you can see,
名称框内 我把这个毛利润率区域命名为 gross_margin
and this is named box for operating margin.
而这个营业利润率区域命名为 operating_margin
So, I just said okay within the gross margin array,
函数公式表示 在毛利润率的范围内
give me an exact match for where the ticker symbol and your- as you can see,
精确匹配股票代码和年份这两个条件
ticker symbol and your are matched and give me
也就是匹配这列股票代码以及这列年份
that particular gross margin or operating margin,
就会返回特定的毛利润率或营业利润率
and plug it in for me into these cells.
然后把值代入这些单元格
So, that's what I did here,
就像这样
and then four operating margin,
对于营业利润率
I reference the array is referring to the operating margin
Index 函数里的范围指明是营业利润率
saying give me that exact ticker symbol and your match and plug in that value.
那就要精确匹配股票代码和年份 并嵌入对应的值
Revenue growth, you're just taking
收入增长的计算方式是
your current year's revenue over your previous year's revenue minus one.
当前年度收入与上一年度收入之比减去 1
What essentially does is it gives you the difference
本质上说 就是利用上一年度收入
between the two years of revenue based on
来计算出两年度收入之差
last year's revenue so you can see how much
这样就可以知道
the revenue growth has occurred in the current year based on last year's revenue.
与去年的收入相比 今年的收入增长了多少
I'm using HPE as a ticker symbol,
本例中 使用的股票代码是 HPE
so you can see all the 3-years historical data.
因此可以看到 3 年的所有历史数据
You can see this looks different for the companies with just two years data,
与只有两年数据的那些公司相比 表格明显不一样
but I delete the financial forecast would actually be for one company,
不过我删掉了只有一家公司的财务预测
for your own company so,
这样
you're going to have this as a dynamic array.
多家公司的数据就会构成动态交互的区域
Okay. So, we have the historical upgrading statistics here and step 1 is done.
那么 得到的就是更新的历史数据 第 1 步也就结束了